# **Simon Rose**

# **Software Engineer**

simon-rose.co.uk

**♀** Sheffield, UK





+447791863017

### Summary

I am an ambitious and driven Software Engineer, experienced in designing and developing full-stack web applications from web-based games to enterprise-level systems. I have a PhD in Computer Science and several years of professional software development experience, across both industry and academia. I have strong interpersonal and teaching skills and exceptional ability in organisation, planning and time management.

# **Experience**

#### Freelance Software Engineer - Simon Rose Software

April 2016 - Present

- Design, development and deployment of full stack web applications, primarily in JavaScript using front-end frameworks (AngularJS, Vue.js and React) and Node.js/Express back-ends with MongoDB.
- Client liason and project management.
- Projects include research software for Loughborough University.

### **Director - Rose Brothers Digital**

Aug 2020 - Present

- Digital marketing business founded by my brother and I.
- Providing bespoke website design and development and SEO services.

#### **Associate Lecturer - Sheffield Hallam University**

Oct 2016 - Oct 2020

- Preparing and delivering teaching content on a number of undergraduate Computer Science and Software Engineering modules.
- Supervising MSc, BSc and BEng students on their final year projects.
- End Point Assessor for the Digital and Technology Solutions Specialist MSc course.
- Student voice 'outstanding' member of staff 2016-17 and 2019-20.

#### Full Stack Software Engineer - 3Squared

Sept 2013 - May 2016

- Developing bespoke web applications in C# using ASP.NET MVC and Web Forms.
- Using web technologies including HTML, JavaScript and CSS.
- Working in Agile teams.
- Code reviews.
- Version control using Git and Team Foundation Server.
- API design and implementation.

# Education

## PhD Computer Science - Sheffield Hallam University

Oct 2016 - Sept 2019

Thesis Title: Developing Children's Computational Thinking Skills using Programming

Supervisors: Dr Jacob Habgood and Dr Tim Jay

# **MComp Software Engineering - Sheffield Hallam University** First Class (Honours)

Award Classification Mark: 86.55%

Sept 2011 - July 2016

#### **Skills**

Programming Languages	Frameworks/Software	Other Skills
<ul><li>- JavaScript (and TypeScript)</li></ul>	- Node.js	- Organised
- C#	- Angular	- Motivated
- C++	<ul><li>- Vue.js (and Vuex)</li></ul>	- Pragmatic
- Java	<ul> <li>React (and Redux)</li> </ul>	- Adaptable
- SQL	<ul> <li>Mocha/Chai/Jest/Cypress</li> </ul>	- Able to lead
- PHP	NET	- Business awareness
- HTML	- MongoDB	- Widely-read
- CSS (and LESS/SASS)	- Photoshop	<ul> <li>Teaching/presenting</li> </ul>
	- InDesign	

# **Example Projects**

Cognitive Function Task May 2020 - July 2020

- An application that allows researchers to flexibly develop and customise cognitive function task assessments.
- Split into three parts: a CMS for managing tasks, an progressive web application for running tasks and a REST API that handles data.
- Developed using Vue.js for the front-end and Node.js/Express for the back-end.
- Research project for the Centre of Mathematical Cognition at Loughborough University.

Pirate Plunder Sept 2017 - July 2018

- Educational block-based programming game.
- Teaches players how and why to use procedures the Scratch programming tool.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack.
- Developed as part of my PhD.

Speakeasy Jan 2016 - May 2016

- Lead programmer in a team of 3.
- Augmentative and alternative communication (AAC) speech generation software designed for children with cerebral palsy.
- Uses semantic compaction to combine chosen words to form more complex sentences.
- MEAN (MongoDB, Express, Angular, Node.js) stack.

#### **Interests**

# Sport

I enjoy playing and watching sport, primarily football and resistance work in the gym. I play 6-a-side football regularly.

#### Reading

I like to read and am always striving to broaden my knowledge and understanding on a wide range of topics. I set myself the goal to read a book a week in 2016 and have continued to exceed this target each year.

#### **Travel**

I am a keen traveller and enjoy backpacking. I have travelled around South East Asia, South America, Japan and several European countries in the last few years.

# References

**Dr Jacob Habgood**Director of Education Partnerships
Sumo Digital
jhabgood@sumo-digital.com

Martin Cooper Senior Lecturer Sheffield Hallam University m.j.cooper@shu.ac.uk James Fox Commercial Director 3Squared james.fox@3squared.com